# JÚLIO ARAÚJO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Porto
- julioaraujo.vercel.app
- <u>Linkedin</u>

### PROFILE

Frontend enthusiast with 2 years of experience, that uses tech like Vue and React to build great user experiences. Motivated to grow professionally, sharing knowledge and accepting new challenges, because i believe they are the step for improvement.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### Sep. 2023 - PRESENT

Farfetch

## **Software Engineer**

- Worked in a agile enviroment using Kanban.
- Made use of React / NextJS to create great user interfaces and apps that feed the company ecosystem.
- Maintain BFF applications using NestJS and GraphOL.
- Worked closely with product team to meet project's goals, requirements and functionality.
- Developed based on standard software engineering methodologies like code reviewing, ensuring coverage of unit, integration, e2e tests.

#### May 2022 - August 2023

Nonius

# **Software Engineer**

- Worked closely with design and product team to meet project's goals, requirements and functionality.
- Made use of React / Vue to create great user interfaces.
- Used Vuetify and SASS to speed up styling workflow.
- Used Vuex for state management.
- Ensured quality of frontend products using e2e tests with Nightwatch.
- Integrated clients services in company HUB using Django.
- Python scripts monitoring VPN status, Printers data from tenants, while using Redis to cache that data and display it in the UI with Chartjs.
- Used Vanilla Javascript for VOD on TVs and to create a composer so tenants could build things like Hotel menus.

# EDUCATION

# 2019-2022 INSTITUTO POLITÉCNICO DA MAIA

 Bachelor In Tecnologias e Informação, Web e Multimédia

# 2017-2019 INSTITUTO POLITÉCNICO DA MAIA

 CTeSP In Tecnologias e Programação de Sistemas de Informação

# SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python
- Typescript, CSS in JS
- React, Vue, NodeJs
- Graphql
- Jest, WebdriverIO
- Git, Gitlab, Jira, Jenkins, ArgoCD
- SQL/NoSQL, Redis

#### INTERNSHIPS

Trackdream (4 months)

## **Software Engineer**

- Angular, Django
- ·PostgresSql for querying the database.

Samsys (6 months)

## **Software Engineer**

- C#, ASP.net and Javascript
- MySQL
- Scrum

## LANGUAGES

- English (C1)
- Portuguese